<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Stanford&#39;s Guide to the Blockchain</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://cs58n.ml/"/>
  <updated>2020-03-12T08:11:03.937Z</updated>
  <id>https://cs58n.ml/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Stanford CS58N Team</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Stanford Student&#39;s Guide to Blockchain</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/introduction/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/introduction/</id>
    <published>1776-03-12T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:11:03.937Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After snacking on donuts at 9 a.m and listening to some of the world’s best blockchain developers at Libra, a group of Stanford students compiled this guide for leading the average person to blockchain enlightenment.</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="Welcome-to-Blockchain-Class"><a href="#Welcome-to-Blockchain-Class" class="headerlink" title="Welcome to Blockchain Class!"></a>Welcome to Blockchain Class!</h2><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://www.memesmonkey.com/images/memesmonkey/3b/3bd950a24a6b8de2fc6fba79e3cb2d08.jpeg" alt="Blockchain Memes exist"></p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Imagine a world where monetary transactions can occur at any instance, a world where your payment can be processed without the need of centralized agencies. Imagine a society in which a reliable form of transactions is common, a society where people can trust others without the need of any intermediary. If you imagine such a thing as a novel invention, then imagine a world of ‘blockchain’.<br>It has been almost a decade since blockchain has become a buzzword for computer science. Though still in its preliminary and experimental stage, blockchain promises a future world where political, economic, and financial institutions will be revolutionized. Our daily lives would transform on an unforeseen scale, and because of this magnitude it is pertinent that we have a great understanding of blockchains underlying principles.<br>In this website, we would like to introduce you to the basic overview of blockchain - from its technical framework to its real-world application to intriguing viewpoints by various scholars.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://101blockchains.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Trying-to-explain-blockchain-meme.jpg" alt="Blockchain Memes exist"></p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Now, we don’t want to come off as experts on the field, however we have delved into the works with blockchain and seen some of its practical uses. Don’t worry nothing in the guide is crazy complicated, and everything should only bring practical value to how you use and see this technology in the world.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://media1.giphy.com/media/Xtg9ygGsjvouF7vZ1w/giphy.gif?cid=790b76117a068db83a4ea40cd3a34f034bb6d67e9ae86b43&rid=giphy.gif" alt="Blockchain Memes exist"></p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>So let’s dive in. How does blockchain even work?</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;After snacking on donuts at 9 a.m and listening to some of the world’s best blockchain developers at Libra, a group of Stanford students compiled this guide for leading the average person to blockchain enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why Should we use Blockchain?</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/why-use-blockchain/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/why-use-blockchain/</id>
    <published>1776-03-11T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:10:20.097Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When people think about blockchain, generally, there are two questions that come to mind:</p><blockquote><p>What makes blockchain better than existing technologies?<br>Why should I use blockchain?</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Why-use-blockchain"><a href="#Why-use-blockchain" class="headerlink" title="Why use blockchain?"></a>Why use blockchain?</h1><p>To put it simply, blockchain provides resiliency, protects data, and provides consensus.<br>The benefits, as <a href="https://www.bernardmarr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bernard Marr</a> puts it, are numerous:</p><ul><li><p><strong>You get a history of activity, not just a snapshot in time.</strong> When you look at a regular database, you’re getting a snapshot of data that’s up to date in that moment in time. Blockchains do this too, but they also maintain a record of all the information that existed before. It’s a database with history, if you like.</p></li><li><p><strong>There’s no one, central point of attack.</strong> The fact that blockchain is a decentralised way of storing and accessing data makes the whole system incredibly secure – because, unlike a centralised database, there’s no one single point of entry for hackers. This makes it particularly useful for recording transactions in a secure manner.</p></li><li><p><strong>And no centralised control.</strong> Because the system of record is decentralised and replicated in its entirety in multiple places, there’s no need for a central administrator and all the costs and infrastructure that comes with it.</p></li></ul><p>These principles lead to making systems that run with blockchain hard to hijack, but at the same time, provide open access for anyone to verify other’s transactions. It is similar to how you can see people’s Venmo transactions with someone else but not see how much they are sending, or how much is in their bank account. To continue this analogy, if someone sent someone money on Venmo, other users would have to reach a consensus of whether this is an actual transaction, then once verified, propagate the transaction to all of the two people’s friends.</p><p>Here are some more cases of when blockchain might come in handy from <a href="https://www.bernardmarr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bernard Marr</a>:</p><ul><li><p><strong>When you want to manage and secure digital relationships or keep a decentralised, shared system of record.</strong> Anytime you want to keep a long-term, transparent record of assets (for example, to record property or land rights), blockchain could be the ideal solution. ‘Smart contracts’, in particular, are great for facilitating digital relationships and transactions. With a smart contract, automated payments can be released when parties in a transaction agree that their conditions have been met.</p></li><li><p><strong>Anywhere a middleman or gatekeeper function is expensive or time-consuming.</strong> For example, most accommodation providers currently have to interact with guests via a centralised aggregator platform, like Airbnb or Expedia (who, in turn, take a cut on each booking). Blockchain could change all that. For example, travel company TUI is so convinced of the power of blockchain, it’s pioneering ways to connect hoteliers and customers directly, so that they can transact via blockchain in an easy, safe and consistent way, rather than via a central booking platform.</p></li><li><p><strong>When you want to record secure transactions, especially between multiple partners.</strong> A traditional database may be good for recording simple transactions between two parties, but when things get more complicated, blockchain can reduce bottlenecks and simplify relationships. For example, shipping conglomerate Maersk is working with IBM to develop a private blockchain platform to connect its various partners and customers across the shipping industry. What’s more, the added security of a decentralized system makes blockchain ideal for transactions in general.</p></li><li><p><strong>Where the data is in constant flux, but you want to keep a record of past actions.</strong> Blockchain is a better, safer way to record activity and keep data fresh, while maintaining a record of its history. The data can’t be corrupted by anyone or accidentally deleted, and you benefit from both a historical trail of data, plus an instantly up-to-date record.</p></li></ul><h1 id="So-when-should-you-not-use-blockchain"><a href="#So-when-should-you-not-use-blockchain" class="headerlink" title="So when should you not use blockchain?"></a>So when should you not use blockchain?</h1><p>Blockchain shouldn’t be used for strictly confidential information. For example, a franchise could have a blockchain for all the sales at different restaurants, but you wouldn’t want a franchise restaurant looking at the other restaurant down the street’s sales. However, you can have a closed blockchain. So with the same analogy, the company could allow only franchise stores to see each other’s sales, but not the general public.</p><p>Also, since consensus needs to be reached for a transaction to be executed, high-speed transactions might not be the best fit. For example, a Bitcoin transaction takes about 10 minutes to fully send. However, companies like Libra are creating new forms of blockchain that can handle over 100,000 transactions per second!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;When people think about blockchain, generally, there are two questions that come to mind:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What makes blockchain better than existing technologies?&lt;br&gt;Why should I use blockchain?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Smart Contracts and the Communication Layer</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/smart-contracts/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/smart-contracts/</id>
    <published>1776-03-10T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:42:12.547Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Smart Contracts</strong></p><p>In its essence, blockchain is a native digital medium for value – that is, it allows for the exchange, transaction and management of anything of value. From money, to music or votes, this concept allows the user to give and receive elements without double-spending.</p><a id="more"></a><p>Now that we’ve taken a deep look into the underlying technology that enables a blockchain (see Figure 1), we can analyze the last layer: the transaction programs. This is the icing on the blockchain cake, as it integrates all the previous layers into a programmable exchange.</p><p><a href="https://imgbb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://i.ibb.co/FJ7V5pM/image1.png" alt="image1" border="0"></a><br>Figure 1 Layer Cake Diagram of blockchain technology</p><h2 id="Current-state"><a href="#Current-state" class="headerlink" title="Current state"></a>Current state</h2><p>There’s a problem common to the very nature of trade that we still haven’t solved properly: trust. A clear example of this can be found in global trade. Imagine the case of a new flower store in California that wants to order a container of tulips from the Netherlands just in time for Valentine’s day. After finding a suitable supplier and receiving a quote for the products, the inevitable question arises: Who should pay first? Should the flower store send the money to the supplier first and risk bankruptcy if the farmer just stops answering its emails? Or should the supplier send its tulips first, and then risk not receiving any money for its flowers?</p><p>Maersk analyzed this situation in <strong><em>2018</em></strong> and found out that, in order to generate trust between two parties in the uncertainty of global trade, 90% of companies use brokers and at least 80 people get involved in building a large paper trail for every shipment that takes place. From banks to third party intermediaries, this is a largely inefficient process – smart contracts bring a simpler alternative.</p><h2 id="What-is-it"><a href="#What-is-it" class="headerlink" title="What is it?"></a>What is it?</h2><p>The concept of a smart contract finds its counterpart in conventional contracts. In this sense, both a smart contract and a conventional contract are a legally enforceable agreement between two (or more) parties. Moreover, both should have an offer, consideration, and acceptance to make it valid. However, the key difference is that the terms in a smart contract are programmed in a computer and then committed to a blockchain. Therefore, they are executed no matter what.</p><p>Both the code and the conditions in the contract are publicly available on the ledger they are a part of, which ensures transparency and accountability from all parts involved. This concept is akin to the system used in your monthly Netflix subscription, where if a month goes by then your credit card is automatically charged.</p><h2 id="How-does-it-work"><a href="#How-does-it-work" class="headerlink" title="How does it work?"></a>How does it work?</h2><p>The principle used in programming smart contracts is based on simple programming logic: if <strong><em>A</em></strong> happens, then do <strong><em>B</em></strong>. In this case, <strong><em>A</em></strong> is called a “trigger event” and it can be used to encode the conditions one of the parties has to meet before a transaction is completed. For instance, a trigger event could be an expiration date or a target price. After all trigger events have been met, then the contract’s code executes.</p><p>Therefore, after the basic conditions have been met, the contract automatically transfers the value to the relevant parties. An interesting property of smart contracts is that value can take multiple forms, from cryptocurrency to documents or objects, which gives it a great flexibility as well.</p><p>Finally, the transfer of value is recorded in the blockchain to allow for accountability – this step is called the settlement. This procedure ensures accountability, and is of great value for auditors given that it enables three important factors:</p><ol><li><p>Each auditor has access to the current state of the chain, including balances and coded contracts</p></li><li><p>Any party can compute the effect of a transaction, since it has access to all the information, and verify its outcome</p></li><li><p>Any party can confirm the existence of any block in the blockchain, which would potentially avoid fraud in transactions</p></li></ol><p>All in all, smart contracts don’t build trust between parties: they eliminate the need for trust altogether. In other words, neither the florist nor the farmer needs to trust each other: they both trust the code with their assets. In theory, it will enable users to build a bullet-proof contract, which only (but surely) executes when certain conditions are met. If one of the parties fails to meet its part of the agreement, the contract simply holds the goods. Certainly, we believe this is a big step in terms of public accountability, since all validators can verify all transactions in the blockchain.</p><h2 id="Looking-forward"><a href="#Looking-forward" class="headerlink" title="Looking forward"></a>Looking forward</h2><p>According to Mckinsey &amp; Co. (2018), potential applications of smart contracts include automation of insurance-claim payouts, healthcare record access for research, and temporary employment contracts. However, some drawbacks of the technology lie in the difficulty of its widespread adoption, the difficulty of learning how to code and revise a contract’s code, and the process to invalidate a contract if a bug occurs or (for instance) one of the parties signs it under coercion. If you’re interested in other practical uses of smart contracts, look into the Applications section for more information.</p><h2 id="Additional-readings"><a href="#Additional-readings" class="headerlink" title="Additional readings"></a>Additional readings</h2><p>Accenture,<a href="https://www.accenture.com/_acnmedia/pdf-79/accenture-blockchain-mapping-trade-routes-to-trust.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Mapping new trade routes to trust</a></p><p>WTO,<a href="https://www.wto.org/english/res_e/booksp_e/blockchainrev18_e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Can blockchain revolutionize international trade?</a></p><p>Mckinsey &amp; Co,<a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/operations/our-insights/blockchain-technology-for-supply-chainsa-must-or-a-maybe" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Blockchain technology for supply chains: a must, or a maybe?</a></p><p><strong>Communication layer</strong></p><p>A blockchain is built on consensus between all blocks when it comes to any individual action. Therefore, the process of building a blockchain needs have a network protocol that allows effective interaction between blocks – this is the role of the communication layer.</p><p>The communication layer undergoes two main procedures when taking a decision: a communication step and a broadcast procedure.</p><p>Imagine the case of proposing the addition of a new block to the blockchain. The communication step would involve the proposal of a new block through the internet, and a group voting procedure via consensus protocol to ensure that dishonest blocks don’t compromise the integrity of the blockchain (see: consensus layer).</p><p>Moreover, after the decision is taken, it must be broadcasted. At the most basic level, any block can communicate directly to its immediate neighbors. However, given that the design of the blockchain allows for some nodes to be separated from others by one (or multiple) degrees of separation, a broadcast method is also employed. Therefore, in these cases, the intermediary nodes can act as a relay for the message, sending it to its nearest neighbors repeatedly. This principle allows for every node to communicate with the entire blockchain, as seen in Figure 2.</p><p><a href="https://imgbb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://i.ibb.co/pJHHLk9/image2.png" alt="image2" border="0"></a></p><p>Figure 2 Relay communication between nodes in a blockchain</p><h2 id="Additional-readings-1"><a href="#Additional-readings-1" class="headerlink" title="Additional readings:"></a>Additional readings:</h2><p>Packt, Exploring Blockchain and BaaS</p><p>David Xiao, The Four Layers of the Blockchain</p><p>Sankar, G et al., A reference Architecture for Blockchain-based Peer-to-Peer IoT Applications</p><p>Lamport, L et al., The Byzantine Generals Problem</p><p><strong>Predictions (!)</strong></p><ul><li>By 2030, Blockchain will be widely used in the management of letters of credit for global trade.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, blockchain is a native digital medium for value – that is, it allows for the exchange, transaction and management of anything of value. From money, to music or votes, this concept allows the user to give and receive elements without double-spending.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Addressing Misconceptions about Blockchain</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/common-misconceptions/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/common-misconceptions/</id>
    <published>1776-03-10T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:11:25.097Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Next Big Thing…Or not?</strong></p><p>Maybe you heard about the next <em>blockchain + big data + AI</em> startup or that at one point, Bitcoin reached a price of $20,000 per Bitcoin. You probably heard them in separate contexts, but like a majority of people, you lumped them into a single category, and there is a very good reason for that: the majority of the modern use of <strong>blockchain</strong> technology has been for financial transactions (with cryptocurrencies).<a id="more"></a></p><p>Despite this, Bitcoin and blockchain are related, but very separate. In general, the word blockchain is a macro-level classification of a series of blocks that are linked together cryptographically. Bitcoin, however, is a cryptocurrency that is powered by a blockchain that stores transactions. That being said, unless your friend’s startup is in the financial technology space, it is probably not using Bitcoin itself. However, they may be using a <strong>blockchain</strong>, as blockchains have applications that are well-beyond the space of finance.</p><p><strong>Useful Properties of Blockchains</strong></p><p>Distributed sources that can be read from and written to have long been used in computer systems (for example, databases are ubiquitous) — however, the properties of blockchains can be exploited to act similarly to databases, but have extra features. For example, the fact that blockchains inherently do not support the removal of blocks make them very powerful for keeping track of accountability. One place in which accountability is very important is a supply chain, where many different entities need to communicate in order to start with raw supplies in one part of the world and end up with a complete product in another part of the world. Because blockchains are inherently very accountable and allow for multiple people to write to them, they could be applied widely in the field.</p><p><strong>Secure…but public</strong></p><p>Even though blockchains are powerful storage systems, there is one thing that they are definitely not — private. Because all validators on a blockchain must agree on new blocks that are being placed, and because anyone can read from the blockchain, the data stored in blocks must be secured. That means that some data, such as health records, can’t easily be stored.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Next Big Thing…Or not?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you heard about the next &lt;em&gt;blockchain + big data + AI&lt;/em&gt; startup or that at one point, Bitcoin reached a price of $20,000 per Bitcoin. You probably heard them in separate contexts, but like a majority of people, you lumped them into a single category, and there is a very good reason for that: the majority of the modern use of &lt;strong&gt;blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; technology has been for financial transactions (with cryptocurrencies).
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Storage Layer</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/storage-layer/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/storage-layer/</id>
    <published>1776-03-10T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:10:10.127Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this article, I will outline what this “storage layer” is in blockchain. The storage layer is the basic foundation on which the blockchain is built. In essence, this layer is just the blocks that link to one another.<a id="more"></a> These blocks are the individual information units (i.e. if a blockchain were storing information about financial transactions, one block would have information about one financial transaction). Blocks have been compared to the page of a ledger or a record book. However, these blocks do not only just store information, they also link to the previous block in order to maintain this “chain.” Visually:</p><p><a href="https://ibb.co/vwcrTgS" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://i.ibb.co/6nypTVk/image1.jpg" alt="image1" border="0"></a></p><p>Depending on the function of the blockchain, each block could have different types of information stored, as well as hashed (i.e. hidden) information attached to it. For most types of blockchains, blocks also store values about who initiated or received the information. Normally, this data ought to be private, so that’s when information gets stored as a hash value– usually the “digital signature.”</p><p>However, the blocks themselves are identifiable as well. That is why (as seen in the visual above) that each block has an associated unique value. Here, hash values are used yet again in order to tell it apart from other blocks. This is the basic outline of what composes a block. For each blockchain, there might be small details such as the types of information stored and the type of information hashed, but the basic premise is maintained.</p><p>For more information about the basics of a block in a blockchain:</p><p><a href="https://learnmeabitcoin.com/beginners/blocks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learn Me A Bitcoin</a></p><p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/blockchain.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain Explained</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;In this article, I will outline what this “storage layer” is in blockchain. The storage layer is the basic foundation on which the blockchain is built. In essence, this layer is just the blocks that link to one another.
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cryptography (public key infrastructure)</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/cryptography/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/cryptography/</id>
    <published>1776-03-10T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:10:42.577Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To first understand cryptography, we must first understand hash functions. Hash functions are mathematical functions used to convert input values into output values that are irreversible.</p><a id="more"></a><p>Blockchain uses a type of cryptography called public key cryptography. It is a system that uses a pair of keys called the public key and the private key. Each individual has each their two pairs; however, the private key is never to be shared. This form of cryptography is used to encrypt messages between two people securely. Any public key can be used for encryption, but to decrypt any message would need the public key that is associated with it. Visually:</p><p><a href="https://imgbb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://i.ibb.co/hVqKg6v/image2.png" alt="image2" border="0"></a></p><p>This is particularly important for blockchain technology because much of the information stored ought to be kept private (such as who conducted a financial transaction), so blockchain’s usability is reliant on the ability to keep this information private to all but the owner.</p><p>For more information on the usage of public key infrastructure in blockchain:</p><p><a href="https://crushcrypto.com/cryptography-in-blockchain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INTRODUCTION TO CRYPTOGRAPHY IN BLOCKCHAIN TECHNOLOGY</a></p><p><a href="https://www.globalsign.com/en/ssl-information-center/what-is-public-key-cryptography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">What is Public-key Cryptography?</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;To first understand cryptography, we must first understand hash functions. Hash functions are mathematical functions used to convert input values into output values that are irreversible.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Interviews</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/interviews/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/interviews/</id>
    <published>1776-03-09T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:10:38.587Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our class recorded a few interviews with other students and with our professor, John Mitchell to give different perspectives on blockchain applications. Click on the three bars to display all the interviews.</p><a id="more"></a><div id="cplayer-97093252"></div><script>(function(){        function loadcplayer() {          if (typeof window.cplayerList === 'undefined') window.cplayerList = {};          if (typeof window.cplayerList["cplayer-97093252"] !== 'undefined') return;          if (!cplayer.prototype.add163) cplayer.prototype.add163 = function add163(id) {            if (!id) throw new Error("Unable Property.");            return fetch("https://music.huaji8.top/?id=" + id).then(function(res){return res.json()}).then(function(data){              let obj = {                name: data.info.songs[0].name,                artist: data.info.songs[0].ar.map(function(ar){ return ar.name }).join(','),                poster: data.pic.url,                lyric: data.lyric.lyric,                sublyric: data.lyric.tlyric,                src: data.url.url              }              this.add(obj);              return obj;            }.bind(this))          }          window.cplayerList["cplayer-97093252"] = new cplayer({            element: document.getElementById("cplayer-97093252"),            playlist: [{"name":"Mark and Marcelo on International Trade","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Mark_Marcelo_IntlTrade.m4a"},{"name":"John Mitchell Part 1","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Mitchell+interview+part+1.m4a"},{"name":"John Mitchell Part 2","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/mitchell+interview+part+2.m4a"},{"name":"Healthcare","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Healthcare.m4a"},{"name":"Samuel on Finance Part 1","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Samuel+Finance+Part+1.m4a"},{"name":"Samuel on Finance Part 2","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Samuel+Finance+Part+2.m4a"},{"name":"Fahad on Finance","poster":"https://identity.stanford.edu/img/SU_New_BlockStree_Red_darkbgrd.png","src":"https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/cs58n.ml/Fahad_Nabi+Interview.m4a"}],            generateBeforeElement: true,            deleteElementAfterGenerate: true,            autoplay: false          });                  }                if (typeof window.cplayer === 'undefined' && !document.getElementById("cplayer-script")) {          var js = document.createElement("script");          js.src = 'https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/MoePlayer/cPlayer/dist/cplayer.js';          js.id = "cplayer-script";          js.addEventListener("load", loadcplayer);          document.body.appendChild(js);        } else {          window.addEventListener("load", loadcplayer);        }      })()</script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Our class recorded a few interviews with other students and with our professor, John Mitchell to give different perspectives on blockchain applications. Click on the three bars to display all the interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Applications of Blockchain</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/applications-of-blockchain/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/applications-of-blockchain/</id>
    <published>1776-03-08T07:52:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:10:51.427Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Credentials"><a href="#Credentials" class="headerlink" title="Credentials"></a>Credentials</h2><p>One of the most promising potentials of blockchain technology is in the realm of credentialing and user identification. Humans have utilized credentialing systems and dealt with issues of trust and verification for millennia.<a id="more"></a> Since 9th century Islamic scholars used an academic certificate called _ijâzah, _we have come a long way in identity confirmation; still, blockchain applications are fairly novel. Since blockchain is a securely encrypted and widely distributed timestamped ledger, many companies, organizations, and entities have been jumping at the opportunity to digitize and secure academic and alternative credentials, and use this technology to affirm identities in an immutable setting.</p><p>For many entities, credentialing and identity verification is an arduous process that often can take months and still exhibit fundamental flaws. Throughout this section, we will explore some of the various applications of blockchain technology in credentialing, and see how this emerging technology is being used to tackle enormous problems such as identity fraud and systematic delays. Below, we delve into the diverse applications of blockchain technology to Health Credentialing, Voting Systems, and Academic Verifications.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://er.educause.edu/articles/2017/4/credentials-reputation-and-the-blockchain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Credentials, Reputation, and the Blockchain</a></li></ul><h3 id="Health"><a href="#Health" class="headerlink" title="Health"></a>Health</h3><p>Currently, physician credentialing normally takes 4 to 6 months to verify information like licenses, medical school and residency completion. During this time it takes to check credentials, it impedes the ability of health care professionals to deliver care. Any updates that need to be made take a long time and are difficult to verify. Additionally, different states have varying compliance regulations that can complicate the credentialing of medical professionals who want to relocate.</p><p>However, with blockchain, this credentialing could instead happen in real time. A study by J.P. Morgan estimated that blockchain could save as much as 80% of the current cost and time invested in physician credentialing today. Since the blockchain can be verified and updated, it would be a secure system to check medical credentials. Additionally, certain parts of the blockchain can be restricted. Users can only access certain parts of the blockchain in order to ensure that a hospital is only looking at the relevant credentials for the doctor or nurse they are trying to hire.</p><p>Check out these sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.medicaleconomics.com/med-ec-blog/blockchain-tool-future-healthcare" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain for the Future of HealthCare</a></li><li><a href="https://www.aha.org/aha-center-health-innovation-market-scan/2018-11-19-blockchain-pilot-aims-streamline-physician" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain Pilot Aims to Streamline Physician Credentialing</a></li><li><a href="https://www.anesthesiabillingbridge.com/6-credentialing-issues-faced-by-medical-practices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">6 critical provider credentialing issues and how automation can solve them</a></li><li><a href="https://hitinfrastructure.com/news/blockchain-could-save-80-of-cost-time-in-physician-credentialing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain Could Save 80% of Cost, Time in Physician Credentialing</a></li></ul><h4 id="Clinical-Trials"><a href="#Clinical-Trials" class="headerlink" title="Clinical Trials"></a>Clinical Trials</h4><p>There are many information transactions that take place today in clinical trials. First, the coordinators of a clinical trial must find patients that are eligible for the study and spread the word about the trial that is occuring in order to find participants. Then, doctors must transfer the medical history of the patients to the coordinators of the trial and relay the treatment course to the participants. Insurance companies must also be updated about the process and treatment in order to cover the cost of the trial. Doctors must be supplied the medicine to give to the patients who are part of the trial and then must relay changes in the patients’ health or status because of the drugs being administered.</p><p>With blockchain, many of these processes can be made faster, more efficient, and more secure. Blockchain can improve communications between doctors, patients, and clinical trial coordinates throughout all stages of the trial process. Additionally, because it is secure and a safe way to store data, it eliminates risk of fraud or errors in data. This ensures that results are truthful and accurately represent any health changes as well as protects from data tampering. Data is shareable yet maintains patient privacy because you can restrict access so that medical history can be shared without any identities being exposed. This way, relevant data about patients can be shared with the trial coordinators without having other private identifying or contact information being shared. Overall, blockchain use in clinical trials could ultimately lead to cheaper drugs for consumers because clinical trials would be able to be done faster and more securely, and thus the cost to create a new drug would be decreased.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://pharmaphorum.com/views-and-analysis/how-blockchain-will-revolutionise-clinical-trials-clinical-trials/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How blockchain will revolutionise clinical trials</a></li><li><a href="https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13063-017-2035-z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain technology for improving clinical research quality</a></li></ul><h3 id="Academic-Credential-Verification"><a href="#Academic-Credential-Verification" class="headerlink" title="Academic Credential Verification"></a>Academic Credential Verification</h3><p>One of the main goals of blockchain technology is the distribution and decentralization of information and resources, and the elimination of intermediaries. As blockchain has spread to various sectors, it has broken into academia in the form of credentialing. A shift from institution-accredited information to student-controlled distribution would empower a generation of students, as it would enable individuals to hold share things such as certificates, degrees, and transcripts in a safe, tamperproof, and trusted manner. Since blockchain is a secure digital ledger of transactions, students would be able to add accomplishments and certifications as a link on this chain, which they could then share with employers, continued education, and other entities. Thus, this could eliminate the universities’ role in continuously validating credentials. Furthermore, a standardized credentialing system would give employers, researchers, and institutions a broader, more heuristic realm of possibility when engaging with students and graduates.</p><p>As of April 2019, a coalition of nine accredited universities have been piloting a program experimenting with digital credentialing through blockchain, including MIT, Harvard, and UC Berkeley. According to an article by EdScoop, “The universities plan to develop a free service through which students can store and share academic credentials from various sources.” The project has the goal of facilitating a global infrastructure to record and validate academic achievements. Most excitingly, it seems academic credentialing is already gaining trust. According to a report by the edtech company Ellucian, 52% of employers and 58% of students surveyed responded they trusted digital credentials. While this sector has a substantial amount to develop and gain steam, blockchain applications in academic credentialing has the ability to revolutionize the way the academia interacts with the rest of the world, and can potentially create a brand new infrastructure in validating academic achievements.</p><p>More Resources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/awecademy/academic-credentialing-on-the-blockchain-38da8ee439b2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Academic Credentialing on the Blockchain</a></li></ul><h3 id="Voting-Alma"><a href="#Voting-Alma" class="headerlink" title="Voting - Alma"></a>Voting - <strong>Alma</strong></h3><p>America, among many other countries, has consistently struggled to optimize the most critical aspect of a functioning democracy: voting. In 2016, individuals in Arizona had to wait up to 5 hours to vote in just one primary election, due to voting stations closing to avoid costs. In the 2018 gubernatorial election in Georgia, a flawed voter registration law kept an estimated 87,000 people from voting in a highly contested race. Currently, there are 19 states that do not require any type of identification from voters prior to voting in a federal election, and there are an estimated 6.9 million overlapping voter registrations. Furthermore, a Princeton professor demonstrated that the innate vulnerabilities in voting machines allow for the removal of the machines memory card, which, if infected with malicious code, could easily steal millions of votes within minutes. It is not disputed that the United States has a long history of systematic voter suppression, flawed registration processes, widespread voter fraud, inconsistent voter ID laws, and vulnerabilities in voting technologies. In a rapidly evolving democracy, voting must be standardized and secured to allow for just and accurate elections. The question remains; how can innovative technologies help fix our voting system?</p><p>Here is where blockchain enters the picture. In Utah in 2016, Blockchain technology was used for the first time in a state election, when Smartmatic, a British online voting company, enabled 59,000 individuals to vote online in the Republican Primary Caucus. The voting took place through a private blockchain utilizing end-to-end encryption to secure the votes. Through facial recognition and key-encrypted user verification, voters are credentialed in private blockchain using personal keys. Thus, when individuals vote, they use their verified identity to add a vote “block” to the chain and ensure their vote is immutable and permanent. Smartmatic’s program director Mike Summer’s was quoted saying this on the matter; “Who thinks the notion of requiring people to go to a particular location at a particular time on a particular day and use a pencil and a piece of paper which is then counted by hand is a good idea? It just seems at odds with how we lead our lives today.” This emerging technology also allowed Utah citizens to vote overseas in 2019, using the Voatz app.</p><p>While promises of secure, standardized voting are enough for many to jump on the blockchain train, there are serious cybersecurity flaws that must be addressed before widespread implementation can happen. Malware on individual devices is a foremost concern in online voting, in which data and votes can be stolen and/or manipulated by malicious parties, since personal devices are nearly impossible to secure. Additionally, many user verification technologies are underdeveloped to the point of near non-viability; facial recognition has high rates of error among minority individuals, as the recognition databases lack diverse data. Finally, the secrecy maintained in our current voting system is meant to ensure elections and votes themselves cannot be bought. If there is a permanent online record of who voted for who, serious ethical questions can be raised about rigged elections. While there have been significant steps taken to innovate our voting system, the infrastructure is not yet ready to be implemented on a large scale in federal elections. Still, blockchain remains an incredibly promising venture for the future of voting.</p><p>Sources:</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://www.apmreports.org/story/2019/10/28/georgia-voting-deadlines-2020-election" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Georgia law prevented 87,000 people from voting last year. And it could have a big impact in 2020</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.thebalance.com/how-the-blockchain-will-change-how-we-vote-4012008" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How Blockchain Technology Can Change How We Vote</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.wired.com/2016/03/security-experts-arent-going-like-utahs-online-primary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Utah’s Online Caucus Gives Security Experts Heart Attacks</a></p></li></ul><h2 id="Cryptocurrency-Finance"><a href="#Cryptocurrency-Finance" class="headerlink" title="Cryptocurrency/Finance"></a>Cryptocurrency/Finance</h2><p><strong>Samuel and Anna</strong></p><p>Money became an abstract concept when its value became independent from the gold standard. Today, money has no store of value, hence it is only “a matter of belief” in the value of it. To unravel the definition of money, it is important to understand the three roles that money has. These roles used to be interconnected but now these three pillars are looked at independently: a unit of value, a medium of exchange, and a store of value. Through cryptocurrency, these three pillars could become once again interconnected as it has a unit of value, medium of exchange and a store of value.</p><p>This field holds by far the most developed and widely-known applications of blockchain. While technology enthusiasts often argue that cryptocurrencies are the inevitable future of financial transactions, there are many notable skeptics who believe they are nothing more than another financial bubble about to burst. No matter on which side you stand, it is essential to better understand the potential and shortcomings of crypto. In this section, we will address this in three main topics: global development, international trade, and digital assets.</p><p>Cryptocurrency is a new software technology market, which has continuously been changing since it began to be developed in 2008. There are constant changes of algorithms, and the mechanics behind cryptocurrency are constantly developing. Hence, this is not representative of the future—as cryptocurrency is an ongoing issue where data is changing and new information and articles are produced about it every day.</p><h3 id="International-Trade"><a href="#International-Trade" class="headerlink" title="International Trade"></a>International Trade</h3><p>In 2018, the global volume of exports reached an all-time high of 19.5 trillion dollars, approximately 23% of the world’s GDP. For centuries, international trade has allowed people from all corners of the world to elevate their standard of living: Latin Americans drive cars made in Japan, Africans wear clothes made in Bangladesh, Europeans consume oranges harvested in California. In every possible perspective, international trade and specialization due to comparative advantage have been two of the driving forces behind global economic growth. That said, processes for international trade are still far from simple: even now, they are almost entirely paper-based, and most countries impose high restrictions on goods imported from other countries.</p><p>As you can guess, blockchain can play a major role in facilitating international transactions in the coming years. Particularly, by keeping track of all the paperwork, blockchain makes transactions more timely, easier to manage and less prone to losses. Also, blockchain’s consensus protocols significantly reduce the likelihood of fraud, as the majority of participants of a transaction have to consent on certain information for it to be uploaded to the blockchain.</p><p>Furthermore, with the use of smart contracts, international trade can become faster and more reliable. Once certain conditions are triggered, the contract is automatically executed, precisely and irrevocably. Under a regime of smart contracts, for instance, it’s impossible for a buyer to not pay the seller after receiving all the imported goods. You can get more information on Smart Contracts in this link (link for the article on Smart Contracts).</p><p>Another important use of blockchain in international trade is related to trade restrictions. By the comprehensive tracking of a product’s supply chain, blockchain enables countries to quickly and reliably check if a good meets their standards. This applies to most environmental, safety, and quality standards. Consider the restriction the European Union imposes on the import of poultry. By using a blockchain supply ledger, EU regulators could know exactly where every bird comes from, as well as their sanitary and transportation conditions. This would allow bureaucrats to make smarter and more accurate decisions.</p><p>In the coming future, the applications of blockchain in international trade will contribute to a safer, quicker and more vibrant world of global transactions.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://www.wto.org/english/res_e/publications_e/blockchainrev18_e.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Can Blockchain revolutionize international trade?</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/264682/worldwide-export-volume-in-the-trade-since-1950/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trends in global export volume of trade in goods from 1950 to 2018</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.wto.org/english/res_e/statis_e/wts2018_e/wts2018_e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">World Trade Statistical Review 2018</a></p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.accenture.com/_acnmedia/pdf-79/accenture-blockchain-mapping-trade-routes-to-trust.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain: Mapping New Trade Routes to Trust</a></p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Credentials&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Credentials&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Credentials&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Credentials&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most promising potentials of blockchain technology is in the realm of credentialing and user identification. Humans have utilized credentialing systems and dealt with issues of trust and verification for millennia.
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>More Applications of Blockchain</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/more-applications/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/more-applications/</id>
    <published>1776-03-07T07:52:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:12:46.807Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Global-development"><a href="#Global-development" class="headerlink" title="Global development"></a>Global development</h3><blockquote><p>It truly is a currency without boundaries, that can empower people and connect a new global economy.” - Nicolas Kokkalis</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><p>Cryptocurrency is an excellent alternative for countries facing an unstable currency that need to secure their assets. It can empower people in developing countries as it facilitates low-cost remittances, and allows people to have a decentralized global bank account where transactions between countries or even between merchants and consumers are facilitated and free of charge. This would take off a financial burden for low-income citizens, as they would be able to make transactions, remittances and lend money without facing high fees.</p><p>“I keep all of my money in Bitcoin. Keeping it in bolívars would be financial suicide: the last time I checked, the rate of daily inflation was around 3.5 percent. That’s only daily inflation; the annual inflation rate for 2018 was almost 1.7 million percent.” Carlos Hernández, a Venezuelan economist, had suffered financial instability due to Venezuela’s hyperinflation, but “cryptocurrencies saved [his] family”. Cryptocurrency allowed people in Venezuela to have financial stability, accessibility and make transactions without causing a financial burden. This provided sovereignty to Venezuelans’ finance without the continuously hyperinflating economy impacting their financial status.</p><p>People in failed societies need a way to back up their own assets so that they do not rely on the government to be financially stable. Countries with an unstable and untrustworthy financial system will be able to perhaps have a stable economy through the use of a global digital currency. This ongoing need for a global currency that is accessible to people has created a movement away from a centralized system to a decentralized system, which is the basis of cryptocurrency: a digital currency available to everyone. Cryptocurrency is considered to be a financial instrument that eliminates the third man/institution; it is an abstract unit that can be used for a token of exchange by anyone with access to the internet. Through cryptocurrency, people could bypass institutional fees, intrusions and obstructions. Cryptocurrency would make money transnational, provide a platform for transactions that are low-cost at a microeconomic and macroeconomic scale, give financial accessibility to citizens with digital access, and even give stability and security to people living in financially unstable countries. Hence, cryptocurrency has been able to provide people sovereignty and agency over their own finances, giving them more stability, so regardless of the country’s financial market they can always be financially stable. This digital currency could then have an impact on people in developing countries, with no financial access, unstable currencies, and high transaction fees (which is a burden especially for low-income citizens).</p><p>Nevertheless, there is a certain irony. Blockchain technology is potentially most useful in situations where there are weak institutions and parties who cannot easily trust each other—for example, in a setting like Zimbabwe, with low state capacity and low trust amidst conflict—but such countries are also often in the weakest position to effectively implement such technology. In the short term cryptocurrency is the best alternative to provide financial stability for people living in countries who are facing an unstable government and currency. However, in the long term, it could have a greater detrimental effect on the local economy as all savings and assets are taken out of the economy, and hence provoke the economy to collapse faster. The government is incompetent of preventing people from moving all of their assets to crypto and taking their money out of the local economy. Hence, cryptocurrency could in the end have greater negative unintended consequences as it would cause the local economy to collapse faster, which would eventually negatively impact the citizens even more. However, could a global currency fix this problem if everyone uses the same digital global currency, where local money would not be withdrawn from the country? Governments need to work concurrently with cryptocurrency internationally, and perhaps even adopt a national cryptocurrency themselves based off a decentralized network where they can still control their economy, and avoid a complete collapse of the economy. But now the question is how would we build a decentralized governance system that gives people a true voice in the decentralized technology systems while still enabling people to be financially stable?</p><p>Cryptocurrency has been able to give the citizens power to control the currency of the country, which can create tension and complexities culturally, politically and economically. Therefore, technologists, politicians, historians, economists must all work together to find a stable and successful financial digital platform that could help people in developing countries, especially countries facing a financial crisis. There is still hope that this can be done through blockchain; as Brian Singer states, “blockchain encryption has a greater ability to bring more of the world’s population out of poverty than anything we have ever seen”. However, for this to be possible we must work together for a bright future.</p><p>Books:</p><ul><li><p><strong>“Money without Boundaries: How Blockchain Will Facilitate the Denationalization of Money”</strong><br>Written by: Thomas Anderson</p></li><li><p><strong>“The End of Monday: The Story of Bitcoin, Cryptocurrencies and the Blockchain Revolution”</strong><br>Written by: Adam Rothstein</p></li><li><p><strong>“Age of Cryptocurrency.”</strong><br>Written by: Paul Vigna</p></li></ul><p>Websites:</p><ul><li><a href="http://www.unrisd.org/brett-scott" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How Can Cryptocurrency and Blockchain Technology Play a Role in Building Social and Solidarity Finance?</a></li></ul><h3 id="Digital-Assets-and-Investing"><a href="#Digital-Assets-and-Investing" class="headerlink" title="Digital Assets and Investing"></a>Digital Assets and Investing</h3><p>Someone who invested 100 dollars in Bitcoin in February 2010 and kept it for 10 years would now have accumulated over 9.2 million dollars. To put this in perspective, an equal investment in Amazon stock would now be worth a little less than 4,000 dollars, and in Warren Buffet’s legendary Berkshire Hathaway a little less than 400 dollars. Even if you believe cryptocurrencies are nothing more than a financial fad, you must admit these are some quite astonishing returns.</p><p>With interest rates at all-time lows, rising global debt, and growing distrust in Central Banks worldwide, digital assets have become an attractive class for many investors. The ability to hold an asset not controlled by any government or central authority appeals to some as the best hedge against the possibility of another massive financial crisis. Furthermore, with the intensification of global migration, cryptocurrencies emerge as a simple and reliable way of securing assets wherever you are in the world. For those who had to leave Syria very quickly during its humanitarian crisis, for example, emergency reserves in crypto would have served as good protection against having to leave all their money in Syrian banks behind. In some ways, investing in cryptocurrencies is defending yourself from the state’s desire for increasing power.</p><p>And Bitcoin is just one of many different cryptocurrencies. Others include Ethereum, Ripple, BCash, and Litecoin. Yet, a feature common to most cryptocurrencies is skyrocketing volatility. It is not uncommon for values to change by 10% in a single day. This creates a new challenge for investors worldwide: if we are truly moving toward a world of crypto, we might have to create stabler ways of storing it. Still, while some investors are unwavering in their belief in cryptocurrencies, many more remain skeptical. In a 2019 interview, Warren Buffett explained one of the reasons why he will never own a single cryptocurrency: “You can’t do anything with it except sell it to somebody else”. Billionaire Mark Cuban has also said publicly that cryptocurrencies hold no “intrinsic value” and that Facebook is making a “big mistake” moving forward with Libra. That said, the best investments in history, as even Buffett would agree, have been the most contrarian. Maybe crypto is just one more.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><p><a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/bitcoin.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">What is Bitcoin?</a></p><p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/billybambrough/2020/02/26/if-billionaire-investor-warren-buffett-ever-buys-bitcoin-you-should-probably-sell/#6583422d1152" target="_blank" rel="noopener">If Billionaire Investor Warren Buffett Ever Buys Bitcoin You Should Probably Sell</a></p><p><a href="https://howmuch.net/articles/biggest-companies-vs-bitcoin-last-decade-performance" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Investment of the Decade: Bitcoin vs. World’s Megacorps</a></p><h2 id="Supply-Chain"><a href="#Supply-Chain" class="headerlink" title="Supply Chain"></a>Supply Chain</h2><p>Using blockchain as a supply chain management system is one of the most exciting applications of blockchain. It can greatly increase “transparency into the provenance of consumer goods— from the source point to end consumption” to ensure that all goods being shipped are tracked and logged from their origin. In addition, blockchain is extremely secure and can help prevent fraudulent products from reaching the shelves.</p><p>For example, in today’s container industry, “paperwork can account for half the cost of transport.” With an efficient blockchain system, this cost can be greatly decreased, lowering product costs to consumers. Additionally, more that “2% of global economic output results from counterfeiting revenues” and a study conducted by Oceana in 2010 to 2012 showed that “seafood is mislabeled up to 87% of the time.” Blockchain is secure and restricts editing access to only the people who should be editing a product and its location or status, thus making this system much more efficient and safer.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://consensys.net/blockchain-use-cases/supply-chain-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blockchain in Supply Chain Management</a></li></ul><h3 id="Aviation"><a href="#Aviation" class="headerlink" title="Aviation"></a>Aviation</h3><p>As odd as it may initially seem, aviation is one of the industries hiding the most potential for blockchain disruption in the near future. Think about it: when it comes to airplanes, it is essential to have the most timely, precise, and reliable data possible. And there’s no better way to do this than through a distributed ledger or blockchain. In this article, we will divide the applications of blockchain in aviation into three main categories: customer relations, aircraft maintenance, and asset management.</p><p><em>Customer Relations</em>: even though loyalty programs have become one of the most important aspects of modern-day commercial travel, they are still full of issues: from big delays for miles to be posted to loyalty accounts to the difficulty of finding actual good uses for your frequent flyer miles, there are many ways in which our loyalty experiences could be made better. Blockchain can help with this. By time-stamping a traveler’s itinerary, for instance, it can make mileage accrual instantaneous. Also, blockchain has the potential to tokenize frequent flyer miles, which would give consumers much more choice and flexibility. We might not be too far from the day in which we’ll be able to pay for groceries, electronics, and even restaurant meals with airline miles.</p><pre><code>_Aircraft maintenance_: maintenance logs are still done in paper, which makes important aircraft information very hard to access and analyze. With blockchain, we can keep close track of the history and condition of every single part of an airliner, as well as maintain an unalterable record of everyone going in and out of a plane. This helps assure maximum travel safety. Blockchain can also move aircraft maintenance from a corrective process, mostly conducted when a problem arises, to a preventive process, conducted even before anything happens._Asset management_: with its detailed record of every single part of a commercial airliner, blockchain can significantly increase the accuracy of aircraft insurance pricing. Also, by improving maintenance processes, it can improve aircraft availability and therefore increase airlines’ revenues. Blockchain can also impact the secondary market for airplanes.  Whenever an aircraft gets resold nowadays, it has to be torn apart and evaluated piece-by-piece. By offering a more accurate assessment of an aircraft’s condition, blockchain can greatly increase resale aircraft value. </code></pre><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources: <a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/aerospace-defence/publications/blockchain-in-aerospace.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data for the life of the aircraft</a></p><p><a href="https://www.bcg.com/en-br/publications/2019/what-could-blockchain-do-airlines.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">What Could Blockchain Do for Airlines?</a></p><p><a href="https://www.accenture.com/dk-en/insight-potential-blockchain-technology-for-airlines" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BEYOND THE BUZZ: THE POTENTIAL OF BLOCKCHAIN TECHNOLOGY FOR AIRLINES</a></p><p><a href="https://www.strategy-business.com/article/How-blockchain-can-improve-the-aviation-industry?gko=9e976" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How blockchain can improve the aviation industry</a></p><h3 id="Health-drugs"><a href="#Health-drugs" class="headerlink" title="Health drugs"></a>Health drugs</h3><p>Currently, the Electronic Data Interchange is the one of the few central databases to track where drugs come from. This database connects distributors to manufacturers, but has many issues in its current implementation. The system is not optimized for the large number of users it has and it is quite costly. Additionally, transactions on the Electronic Data Interchange do not happen in real-time so updates can be quite slow. The system is also lacking in its security and is prone to data breaches and counterfeit drugs.</p><p>With blockchain, medical institutions can easily see how a product travels from the manufacturer to the dispenser. If there are any tainted drugs, medical institutions could find where the original source is and stop any more people from obtaining the drugs immediately. Additionally, since blockchain is secure, this can also stop drug counterfeiting to ensure that all drugs are safe and come from the correct places. It can also prevent confidential information from being leaked with utilization of zero knowledge proofs. In fact, after completing a pilot program with the US Food and Drug Administration, “25 leading pharmaceutical manufacturers, distributors, logistic partners, and other representatives of the pharma supply chain have published a report arguing in favor of adopting blockchain technology to track and trace prescription drugs.” Movement has already started towards utilizing blockchain to track drugs in the health sphere and will hopefully continue as blockchain technology becomes more mainstream.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.computerworld.com/article/3439843/how-pharma-will-soon-use-blockchain-to-track-your-drugs.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How pharma will soon use blockchain to track your drugs</a></li><li><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/big-pharma-urges-fda-to-use-blockchain-for-drug-tracking" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Big Pharma Urges FDA to Use Blockchain for Drug Tracking</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youredi.com/blog/the-most-common-edi-challenges" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Most Common EDI challenges</a></li></ul><h3 id="Food-and-Produce"><a href="#Food-and-Produce" class="headerlink" title="Food and Produce"></a>Food and Produce</h3><p>How will blockchain make an impact on our food system? Blockchain’s capability of tracking ownership records and tamper-resistance can be used to solve urgent issues such as food fraud, safety recalls, supply chain inefficiency and food traceability in the current food system. The most common use of blockchain in food and agriculture supply chains is to improve traceability; however it can also have several other uses, such as data transparency, balancing the food market and creating more responsibility within the industry. In terms of traceability it enables companies to quickly track unsafe products back to their source and see where else they have been distributed, in order to maintain a solid reputation by protecting their consumers through placing their health as a priority. This will be possible with the upcoming application of blockchain in the food supply chain, which further has the potential to prevent illness and save lives, as well as reduce the cost of product recalls.</p><p>Food traceability is the center of food safety, because the food industry is extremely vulnerable to making mistakes that would ultimately affect human lives, such as when a foodborne disease threatens the public health, the first step to root-cause analysis is to track down the source of contamination and there is no tolerance for uncertainty. This tracking must be done to protect future consumers, in order to locate the area that was supplying food that causes foodborne disease and then stop production until finding a solution to the foodborne disease. Currently, we have a tracking system that is costly, slow, and not reliable as it is hard to keep track of so much data. Nevertheless, blockchain is able to solve all of these problems, hence in the long run keeping the public’s health strong. Furthermore, blockchain also adds value to the current market by establishing a ledger in the network and balancing market pricing. Farmers are able to access correct and exact data on how much consumers want and how much they are willing to pay for it. This will help create a market with a stable equilibrium, where farmers and consumers will maximize their surplus, by eliminating third parties and creating a marketplace with immense transparency.. Furthermore, companies that buy or invest in agricultural products have an inherent interest in having information about the product before they commit to a purchase. Hence, blockchain will be able to reveal this data about the supply chain, perhaps increasing sales as companies and individuals will be more confident about their investment/purchase as they will have access to the supply chain.</p><p>For example, Walmart has started to use a blockchain to track the source of their fresh food. They claim that the time needed to “trace the firm’s provenance has dropped from seven days to just 2.2 seconds,” a very dramatic shift. Because of this large decrease in the amount of time it takes to find the origins of various products, blockchain can help stop dangerous food contamination. For example, in June 2008, it was found that there were large “quantities of milk and infant formula across China adulterated with melamine”. This resulted in over 300,000 people being affected, with 6 babies dying and another 54,000 being hospitalized. Because it was difficult to track where the infected products were coming from, contaminated products continued to be sold and spread over China. With blockchain, since it is so fast to track where products originate, an outbreak like this can be prevented.</p><p>There are already blockchain companies that are deeply invested in the food sector, such as Bext360 which utilizes a combination of IoT, blockchain, machine learning, and artificial intelligence to build a fully-transparent food supply chain. This company has been able to provide the SaaS platform to growers and different players along the value chain for sharing data and tracking progress.</p><p>If you want to learn more, here are our sources:</p><ul><li><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/walmarts-foray-into-blockchain-how-is-the-technology-used" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Walmart’s Foray Into Blockchain, How Is the Technology Used?</a></li><li><a href="https://qz.com/1323471/ten-years-after-chinas-melamine-laced-infant-milk-tragedy-deep-distrust-remains/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ten years after China’s infant milk tragedy, parents still won’t trust their babies to local formula</a></li><li><a href="https://www.plugandplaytechcenter.com/resources/how-blockchain-will-transform-food-supply-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How Blockchain will Transform the Food Supply Chain</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/cultivati/six-ways-blockchain-is-being-used-in-food-and-agriculture-supply-chains-68a7305fd533" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Six Ways Blockchain is Being Used in Food and Agriculture Supply Chains</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h3 id=&quot;Global-development&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Global-development&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Global development&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Global development&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It truly is a currency without boundaries, that can empower people and connect a new global economy.” - Nicolas Kokkalis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wrapping Up</title>
    <link href="https://cs58n.ml/conclusion/"/>
    <id>https://cs58n.ml/conclusion/</id>
    <published>1776-03-01T07:52:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T08:09:23.717Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Congratulations"><a href="#Congratulations" class="headerlink" title="Congratulations"></a>Congratulations</h1><p>You now are empowered to go share blockchain with all your friends!<br>We hope you enjoyed this guide and that you learned a lot.</p><p>Now go out and buy a latte at Starbucks with Bitcoin with no fear…</p><div class="twitter-wrapper"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><a href="https://twitter.com/jespow/status/1128029728437260289" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></blockquote></div><script async defer src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Congratulations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Congratulations&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Congratulations&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Congratulations&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;You now are empowe
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
